LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
Angels and demons were circling over me,
Crossing a brambly path of stars and milky ways.
He who does not perceive his calling,
does not know true happiness.
Watch in awe! Watch in awe!
Flying in glory, Flying in glory
I am calling, calling now. Spirits rise and falling.
To be with you longer
Calling, calling...
in the depth of longing
To stay myself longer
The flow may swallow you, flying in glory
W-What's happening?
Hey, who's in that thing?
Hey! Stop!
What? It stopped...
Hey, what's going on?
This is what you wanted... Kago?
Proof of
Recklessness
For now, we don't see any
differences between each of them.
That means you lack uniqueness.
Uniqueness?
I would rather you say that every
Tachikoma has the same specs.
But that wouldn't be exciting.
I'll give you a little treat.
Natural oil.
Hey, are you sure you want to give it that?
It might learn strange things.
Don't worry.
This is love for my machine.
Whoa! This is way different
from the usual synthetic oil!
Yup!
Major!
Get 6 Tachikomas ready, with full armour.
Is something wrong?
36 minutes ago at Kenbishi
Heavy Industry's Manoeuvres Dome,
their new multi-legged tank
began to go out of control...
We know that the guy on board is using the
identification code from this machine's designer,
Takeshi Kago, who died a week ago.
But no other details for now...
No claim of responsibility or demands so far, but...
bearing in mind the situation at
Harima Education Institution Lab-City.
The Department of Interior suggested
the possibility of a terrorist attack,
so they requested us,
Public Safety Section 9, to deploy and stop it.
We've been informed that the tank
went wild during the final tune-up.
If the problem was a flaw in the
security system hardware or software...
The Ground SDF, who was considering officially adopting
the tank, really just wants to pin all the blame on Kenbishi.
They never change...
They'll only help us if this is
declared to be a terrorist act.
Trying to look good won't help national defence.
By the way, you're going to fight against a tank
you don't know the specs of, using Tachikomas?
They're not altogether useless.
Way to go Major!
Are you sure?
Major! The tank has changed direction, and is
leaving the Harima Education Institution Lab-City.
This is our chance!
Techno-Line, stretching from the academy city,
is an exclusive road cut through the mountains.
it was created from a mountain trail.
There are only farms and villages around.
Okay, we're going to finish off the
tank while it's on Technology Road.
Pazu, check if any terrorist organisations that oppose cyberbrain
or cyborg technology have issued a claim of responsibility.
Bouma and Saitou, go ahead and set up
an ambush on Harima Techno-Line.
Snipe it from where we won't do any
damage to the area, and stop it!
Togusa, you will meet up with the Chief at Kenbishi
and investigate why the tank went out of control.
Batou and I will lure the rampaging
tank with the 6 Tachikomas.
That is your task.
Don't cry when you get
blown up by that tank, okay?
Harima Education Institution Lab-City,
is where our neuro-chips were made, isn't it?
A triumphant return home!
Stop chit-chatting, or the Major will scold you!
We are the Mobile Armoured Riot Police!
Explain the situation!
Give me a status report!
Yes!
According to our reports,
the tank will appear soon.
Captain!
So far, it has only destroyed its fellow
tanks, and hasn't attacked anyone else.
Open the road and leave everything to us.
Wow!
Don't gawk at it too much and
get into its field of vision!
Let's go!
That's the first time I've seen Section 9...
They really do exist...
We will maintain this distance and continue
to keep watch until the ambush point.
Jigabachi, is the army just
going look on with folded arms?
It's just insurance and containment
for Kenbishi Heavy Industry.
Anyway, what the heck does this tank want?
We don't even know where it's headed.
Is there really someone inside that thing?
Even if we don't have a chance against it,
being ignored like this really makes me mad!
Would you like to jump in front of it, then?
Just kidding...
I'll wait for the report from Oyaji and Togusa.
Note: Batou calls Aramaki "Oyaji", meaning Old Man
Major! I looked through 20 of the 23
organisations which fit the search criteria,
but none of them have issued a claim of responsibility for this incident.
Okay, then look through the remaining 3,
and if you can't dig out any information,
search them in a different way.
How about we just write this off as a yukai-han,
a tank thief, or an AI malfunction?
Note: A Yukai-han
delights in the reactions
to his crimes
Even the actions of a Yukai-Han or a
tank thief are considered terrorism.
We can't dismiss that fact that there
might be a fault in AI completely.
but we will wait for the
report from the chief for that.
There is a technician named Ooba who also
worked on the development of the tank,
a colleague of the late Kago Takeshi.
I hear he was working on maintenance of the
tank until right before the situation occurred.
You guys find out everything he
knows about what the tanks wants.
I will be meeting with the heads of Kenbishi.
Got it!
You're Toshio Ooba,
the development manager for the tank, right?
W-what, y-yeah...
In order to minimise the damage...
We want you to hand over your
information on the new tank immediately.
This is all of it, right?
Y-yes...
Major! I'll send you the data on the tank,
that Kenbishi Heavy Industry gave us.
Confirmed.
I'll be able to get something out of this.
So in the end, all we did was stare at this clunky tank's ass?
We're almost at the ambush point.
Saitou! Ready?
Almost...
Is this good?
Yeah.
Stand back Major.
Not yet! I'll wait until the last
second, so we don't alert it.
Satellite link established.
Major!
Okay!
Chief?!
Major, the data from the
"Hawk's Eye" has been stolen.
He seems to be linked with the satellite.
Give me one more chance with my naked eye!
It seems, you didn't give us all
of the information on the tank.
Withdraw and meet up with us!
Roger!
Is he going to take the highway?
He probably has somewhere he wants to go quickly.
Jigabachi's leaving...
It's almost time for the news
censorship to be broken...
No sign of any terrorist organisations...
So unless Kenbishi admits
that this is their fault...
The army will pretend to know nothing about this.
I guess we'll have to stop this ourselves.
Let's put our hopes in the Ape-Man.
Looks like we can't take it easy...
It's going to be a totally different story,
depending on which way he goes at the fork.
You must have known the answer the Army
would give us, without even asking them.
The rest is up to whether or not you can trust
us, Public Safety Section 9.
We spent 6 years developing the H-A-W-206!
You cops can't guarantee we won't
be damaged by revealing the specs!
That's assuming someone will purchase it.
At this rate, that promotional vehicle
bearing the Kenbishi logo...
will be showing a demonstration of the worst kind.
Is that what you want?
Can you please stop the tank with your tanks?
What are you so worried about?
Why will you not tell me?
You made that tank, didn't you?
Why do you think it went out of control?
Do you really not know?
We're not really questioning you as a suspect...
Will you help us?
Or, do you have a reason that you can't tell us?
Batou! We're going to verify
which way it wants to go.
Isn't it going to the city?
Don't get shot!
Scatter!
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay!
Wait there for rescue, okay?
Okay...
He's lucky, he broke!
He might get a structural analysis!!
Chief! He's headed for the bridge!
It might be our last chance
to use the anti-tank missile!
Ask them if the missile will be of any use.
If we fail, we might destroy the bridge, which would
cost the taxpayers 4 times as much as SPring-8 did!
Spring-8 is the worlds most powerful synchotron,
it cost roughly $1bn to build
Did you hear that?
What do you think, Development Manager?
When it gets to the other side of the
bank, it will enter the city.
Once it gets there,
we'll have fewer ways of stopping it!
You shouldn't use the missile.
Since we think it is using Mode L,
most wireless guided missiles would be jammed.
Even a laser guided missile?
For laser guidance, the tank will give out
deceptive signals to make the missile miss.
Even with wire guidance,
if fired from more than 300 metres away,
the tank will hack it more than 90% of the time,
and possibly send the missile
back at the sniper himself.
If you had held your tongue,
that might have been good advertisement.
Chief, we know who's in the tank.
Who's driving that thing?!
Takeshi Kago.
Did you say Takeshi Kago?!
He died a week ago!
Yes, I heard.
According to him,
he connected Kago's brain to the tank's AI.
How could you do such a thing!
Well... Because it was Kago's will...
Major? Are you listening?
The tank's destination is Takeshi Kago's home.
Here's the destination...
It's close...
Yeah, we're in deep trouble.
We think his objective is to
take revenge on his parents.
Kago displayed a genius for designing tanks,
and was recruited when he was still in college.
His body was very weak,
and he was told by the doctors
that unless he became a cyborg,
he wouldn't be able to make
it to his twentieth birthday.
However, because of his religion,
he wasn't allowed to even use a cyberbrain.
He lived to be 28 because of his
deep devotion to designing tanks.
Ooba, grew up in similar circumstances,
but survived by becoming a cyborg.
So Ooba executed Kago's will, which was that when his
body died, he would be released from his religion.
So, when that happened,
he wanted his brain to be connected to the tank.
It's me.
Get me Ishizuka at the Awaji precinct.
So, why does Kago want to
take revenge on his parents?
Before Kago died,
he blamed his parents for his weak body.
Whenever something happened,
he always said he wanted a steel body.
So when he was released from his
life, he would be able to get a
steel body without going against
the teachings of his parents.
Kago entrusted his dream to Ooba...
My my, what a stubborn guy!
It looks like the destination is around here.
Anyway, let's keep after it!
Wanna try a suicide run!?
The tank has finally entered the city.
There are no casualties so far,
But, we can't be sure from now on.
There will be no casualties.
P-President?
I need to leave Kenbishi
intact for future generations.
Thank you for your cooperation.
We're going to use the wires!
Aim for the tank's legs!
Roger!
Cut the wires!
Physical attacks are useless against him.
Don't do anything stupid.
It's an army's tank,
you're going to get your brain toasted!
Besides, you can't even connect to it via wire!
I'll do what I can!
How long until we're within shooting range?
About two minutes.
Major!
Major! No more! Stop!
Stop!
Chief!
The monkey finally persuaded the raccoon...
Note: He means that Aramaki
persuaded Kenbishi's President
Kenbishi's Anti-Multi-Legged Tank weapon...
If they had that,
they should have given it to us earlier!
It finally stopped...
What an adhesive...
Chief! Give me the passcode
to unlock the attack barrier.
I'll open the hatch and take out Kago's brain.
If he didn't have the defence barrier of a
tank, it would be just a defenseless brain...
Batou! Give me a hand!
Sure!
Any physical traps?
I think it's okay, but be careful...
Takeshi.
Is that you, Takeshi?
What the heck?! Why aren't they somewhere safe?
Did you stop it?
They burned Kago's brain just now...
Kago...
Shit, did he hate his parents that much?
Nah...
Hm?
When I fried Kago's brain,
for just a moment, I felt his thoughts.
"How do you like it, Mother?
My new steel body."
A weird feeling between pride... and revenge...
That's enough.
It was probably an illusion.
I hope so...
We don't have any way to confirm that now...
She's so cold and human
It's something humans do
She stays so cold in her soul, she's so number 9
She's incredible math
Just incredible math
And is she really human?
She says there's something new
But when you live in flower just a mountain bloom
I smell lithium now
Smelling lithium now
How... is she what she doesn't say
She doesn't sat
She doesn't say
How is she when she doesn't suffer
I wonder what she does when she wakes up
When she wakes up
Androids committing mass suicide together,
surely a major scoop for the mass media.
Crimes committed by average citizens...
Do you believe in the existence of souls?
The "Laughing Man" case...
To tell you the truth, this case will be annoying.
"Interceptor"
A new version of an undetectable machine...
and audio-visual perception device...
Now we have all of the pieces of the puzzle.
Want to try some feint manoeuvres?